JOSEPH MEUS

Denver, CO 80204 | Phone: 563-581-3605 | Email: meusjoseph21@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/joseph-meus-4b8b071b4/ GitHub: https://github.com/meusjoseph21

SUMMARY

Full-stack developer with a preference towards front-end development with an education in biology and a determination to keep expanding skills and experience. Capable at working in a high stress environment and meeting tight deadlines all while creating intuitive and effective applications. Well known for determination, willingness to learn, and problem solving in the face of adversity.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Code Based Skills: HTML, CSS, Javascript(ES6), JQuery, Node.js, Materialize, Bootstrap, VSCode, MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars, Inquirer, API/AJAX, Github, Heroku, jawsDB, Atlas, Jest, Postman, Robo3t, Mongoose, React, NPM

Other Skills: Google Drive, Photoshop, Lightroom, Premiere Pro, After Effects, Illustrator

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Certificate: Denver University, Denver Colorado | 2020

Bachelor of Science Biology: Carroll University, Waukesha Wisconsin | 2019 PROJECTS

Meal-Matcher | Github: https://bit.ly/3m7QCs3 | Link: https://bit.ly/3447iLb

- Meal Matcher is a recipe book that searches for recipes from the MealDB recipe API based on the ingredients a user searches. Users can then save and remove recipes from their recipe book.
- Role: Wireframing design, Developing Javascript functions, implementing CSS layout
- Tools Used: Javascript(ES6), Materialize, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS

HotelMotel |Github: https://bit.ly/2W6u54E | Link: https://bit.ly/37WMfLs

- Hotel Motel is a property management application designed specifically for smaller boutique style hotels. This application allows hotel employees to create reservations easily all with a couple clicks.
- **Role:** Wireframing design, Developing Javascript functions, implementing CSS layout, Developing Sequelize database, and creating HTML/API routes
- Tools Used: Javascript(ES6), Materialize, HTML, Sequelize, Express-handlebars, Vanta.js, Express

Pandemic Tracker | Github: https://bit.ly/3a3pQ1W | Link: https://bit.ly/3442mpm

- Pandemic Tracker allows users to observe real time global data of the COVID-19 virus. With Pandemic Tracker users can keep up with news and explore global coronavirus numbers all on an interactive UI.
- Role: Mongoose data seeding, front-end splash page design, site navigation, and API calls
- Tools Used: React Globe, MERN, Bootstrap, React Particles, and Axios

EXPERIENCE

Ski Technician 2019 – 2020

One Stop Ski Shop; Steamboat Springs, Colorado

Collaborated with a team to drive marketing initiatives. Managed data, monetary gains, and customer information.

- Generated \$100,000.00+ in revenue for the holiday season by leveraging early reservations.
- Increased web revenue in and out of ski season by revamping user experience on the company website.
- Improved efficiency by expediting the rental process through implementation of an ipad based rental.

Server 2018 – 2019

Grimaldis Pizzeria; Brookfield, Wisconsin

Coordinated with a team to optimize the dining experience, managed revenue, and mentored trainees.

Promoted from host to desired position as a server within three weeks of employment.

Head Counselor 2017– 2020

Gold Arrow Camp; Lakeshore, California

Oversaw team members and campers. Administered scheduling and communicated with parents and counselors.

- Acquired a promotion from Group Counselor to Head Counselor in the 2018 summer season.
- Served as the leader in implementing Mental Health Certification for all Group Counselors in 2019.